Guide to the Records of the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland 1895-2021 MS 3034
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Financial, 1896-2011
  - Subseries III.C. Banking and Investment records, 1938-2000
    - Bank of New York | Safety Deposit Box, 1990-1994 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 19)
  - Subseries III.D. Miscellaneous financial records, 1898-1995
    - Bequests, 1981-1995 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 20)
    - Donations, 1898-1942 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 21)
    - Scholarship Recipients, 1982-1986 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 22)
    - Scholarship Recipients, 1987-1994 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 23)
- Series IV. Membership, 1895-2021
  Restricted
  Restrictions apply to "Subseries IV.B. Membership Applications and Genealogical Proofs, 1895-2019." See the note below.
  Series IV is organized in two subseries:
  Subseries IV.A. Subseries IV.A. Membership registers, directories, record books, 1895-2019
  Subseries IV.B. Membership Applications and Genealogical Proofs, 1895-2019 (RESTRICTED)
  Subseries IV.A contains various iterations of published record books issued by the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland in 1907, 1913, 1933, 2017, and 2019, as well as membership directories printed between 1915 and 2014/15. These list members by name and unique membership number, and supply brief outlines of their qualifying and supplemental ancestry.
  Subseries IV.B contains original applications for membership in the DHD, which document the lineage of each member back to her qualifying ancestor(s). Supplemental applications provide similar information for additional ancestors from whom members descend. Restrictions apply to this portion of the collection; see the note below.
  - Subseries IV.A. Membership registers, directories, record books, 1895-2021
    - Membership register 1-377 [bound volume], 1895-1934 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12)
    - Membership register 378-721 [bound volume], 1934-2006 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13)
    - Membership register 1-716, 2005 December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 14)
    - Supplementals notebook, 1934 May - 1965 March (Offsite-box 5, Folder 15)
    - First Record Book of the Society of the [sic] Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of the State of New York [sic], 1907 (Offsite-box 4-A, Folder 8)
    - Second Record Book of the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland [5 copies], 1913 (Offsite-box 4-A, Folder 9-10)
    - Third Record Book of the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland [3 copies], 1933 (Offsite-box 4-A, Folder 11)
    - Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Historical Records, 1895-2017, Including Reprints of the Society's Original Record Books [2 copies], 2017 January (Offsite-box 4-A, Folder 12-13)
    - Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland. Register of Members, 1895-2019 [3 copies] (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 1-3)
    - Membership directories [published], 1915-1957 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 4)
    - Membership directories [published], 1960-1970 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 5)
    - Membership directories [published], 1973-1999 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 6)
    - Membership directories [published], 2002-2009 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 7)
    - Membership directories [published], 2010-2013/14 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 8)
    - Membership directories [published], 2014/15 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 9)
    - Membership directories [published], 2008, 2011/12, 2016/17, 2017/18, 2020/21 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 10)
      This folder includes three issues of the newsletter "We Gather Together," for 2018-2021.
    - Honorary member certificates, 2013 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 10)
    - Necrology [deceased members], B-M, 1981-2013 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 11)
    - Necrology [deceased members], P-W, 1981-2013 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 12)
    - Circular of Information, undated (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 13)
    - Membership applications (blanks) and instructions, undated (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 14)
    - Candidates for admission to membership, 1923-1991 (Offsite-box 4-B, Folder 15)
  - Subseries IV.B. Membership Applications and Genealogical Proofs, 1895-2019
    In transferring this collection to the New-York Historical Society, the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland (DHD) stipulated that the material under "Subseries IV.B. Membership Applications and Genealogical Proofs, 1895-2019," containing membership applications, supplemental applications, and working proof files, "be made available for scholarly research... 100 years after that member's birth year" (birth data is recorded with a member's name and unique number on their application). As the New-York Historical Society cannot revisit the collection annually to determine which applications have passed a century and should be deemed open, interested researchers should contact the DHD for details: www.hollanddames.org.
    - Original Applications 1-99 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 21, Volume 1)
    - Original Applications 100-200 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 21, Volume 2)
    - Original Applications 201-300 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 21, Volume 3)
    - Original Applications 301-400 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 22, Volume 1)
    - Original Applications 401-500 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 22, Volume 2)
    - Original Applications 501-600 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 22, Volume 3)
    - Original Applications 601-781 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 23)
      Missing numbers 620-622, 624, 627-629, 637, 639.
    - Original Applications 782-825 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 24)
    - Original Applications 826-846 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 25)
    - Original Application 835 and proof materials (in folder by membership number) (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    - Original Applications 847-870 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 26)
    - Original Applications 871-878 and proof materials (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2-9)
    - Duplicate Applications 507-599 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 27, Enclosure 1)
      Contains numbers 507, 530-541, 597, 599.
    - Supplemental Applications 1-33 (bound volume) [spine reads "1 to 34"] (Offsite-box 27, Volume 1)
    - Supplemental Applications 35-52 (bound volume) [spine reads "35 to 54"] (Offsite-box 27, Volume 2)
    - Supplemental Applications 54-80 (bound volume) [spine reads "54 to 81"] (Offsite-box 27, Volume 3)
    - Supplemental Applications 112-263 (bound volume) [spine reads "170 to 263"] (Offsite-box 28, Volume 1)
    - Supplemental Applications 270-370 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 28, Volume 2)
    - Supplemental Applications 374-419 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 28, Enclosure 1)
      Contains numbers 374, 382, 383, 386, 403, 419.
    - Supplemental Applications 423-540 (in folders by membership number) (Offsite-box 28, Enclosure 2)
      Contains numbers 423, 466, 478, 479, 497, 510, 540.
    - Duplicate Supplemental Applications 60-114 (bound volume) (Offsite-box 29, Volume 1)
    - Duplicate Supplemental Applications 115-193 (bound volume) [spine reads "115 to 187"] (Offsite-box 29, Volume 2)
    - Microfilmed applications (Offsite-box 29, Enclosure 1)
      Eleven reels containing
      01) Original Applications 1-200 & Applicant List
      02) Original Applications 201-500
      03) Original Applications 501-600
      04) Original Applications 601-716
      05) Original Applications 690-B-781
      06) Original Applications 599-732
      07) Original Applications 814, 838
      08) Supplemental Applications 1-80
      09) Supplemental Applications 60-263
      10) Supplemental Applications 270-370
      11) Supplemental Applications 374-541
    - Miscellaneous genealogical proofs (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1-213)
      Supporting genealogical documentation for membership applications:
      4, 31, 50, 52, 54, 69, 93, 95, 101, 110, 119, 121, 124, 149-154, 157, 160-163, 166, 168-170, 174, 176, 178, 180, 183-184, 186, 188-190, 192, 196-206, 211-214, 216-221, 223-224, 226-227, 230-232, 234, 236-237, 240-241, 245, 250-253, 256-261, 263-266, 268-274, 276, 279-280, 282-288, 291-296, 300, 303-304, 307, 314, 317-323, 325-326, 328, 330, 333, 335-337, 339-340, 343-349, 351-352, 354, 360-361, 363, 369-374, 376-377, 379-383, 386-389, 391, 394, 397-398, 401-402, 406-407, 410-416, 418-419, 421, 423, 429, 432-436, 438, 442-445, 448-450, 453-463, 465-473, 475-478, 483, 561, 593.
    - Loose documents and miscellaneous papers (2 folders) (Offsite-box 30, Folder 214-215)
      Includes Somerville birth certificate; Polheim notes; proof of eligibility copy of ancestor Pieter Wyckoff; Mrs. Ashbel Welch letter regarding bible and family bible information, with photographs; lineage of Miss Alice Louis Canoune notes; letter to Mrs. Holbrook in 1907; Philip Peterre Schuyler notes; note regarding Familien Stuyvesant en Bayard; Note regarding Rev. Bogardus.